Excuse me bro, is this your Rolls-Royce?
What do you do for a living?
Meet the most interesting man on
the planet, otherwise known as Abdullah Kudrath.
Over the last decade, AK has
not only been an emergency room doctor,
but he has emerged as one of
the most prominent entrepreneurs throughout Houston, Texas
by creating over seven companies.
We've got a Lamborghini Urus
SUV with a wide body kit.
Over here you see a red Ferrari 458 naturally aspirated.
This is definitely my childhood dream car.
So this is the Lamborghini Diablo.
I sat down with him to figure out
how he was able to build multiple eight-figure businesses
all while being able to
save lives on a weekly basis.
The first time I felt like I needed
to go from being a doctor to a businessman
was actually when I was doing
a medical trip in East Africa.
I realized there's just one person,
there's one doctor with a medical bag.
I could barely scratch the surface of any real problem.
But I realized if I could learn
how to build institutions and understand operations,
I can build entities that last a lot longer.
AK revealed to me some of
the most fascinating lessons that he's learned
from being a doctor for some of
the wealthiest people in the entire world.
People don't care about anything when
their health is on the line.
And that's actually really important because
we can really get caught up
in our pursuit for business and money.
Millions of dollars and they just struck
it big and millions are coming in.
And they're telling me, you know,
doc, that means nothing to me.
I wish I could just have my belly back.
This guy had stomach cancer.
He's like, trade it all if
I could have my belly back.
In this interview, you will learn
from one of the most successful entrepreneurs
throughout the entire country.
How to find someone who can do it.
Create success and create wealth no
matter what industry you are in.
What's going on, everyone?
Welcome back to another episode
of 10 questions with a millionaire.
I'm James and I'm out in
Houston, Texas with a very special guest.
We're here with AK today, who's an ER
doctor, but he's not just an ER doctor.
He's also a serial entrepreneur, owns
and has been building tons of businesses
over the last numerous years out in Houston, Texas.
So could you give a little bit
of an introduction, a background on yourself,
where you started and kind of what you're doing today?
Because I will say you're
probably one of the most interesting
persons I've ever met and had a conversation with.
Well,
I appreciate that.
Yeah, my name is AK.
I am formally trained as an emergency room doctor.
I still do that.
I love being a doctor and working in the ERs.
But I've also branched out.
I've focused on business and
entrepreneurship, started with emergency department
and I've built several of those.
Then I've diversified a little bit to
create a physician group where I hire
other doctors to work in outside hospitals.
And then I diversified into other industries.
So we have a limo.
We have a limo company, an office
space company, learning some real estate development,
building some lake homes, a Botox and filler company.
We built a lounge in Midtown
and maybe a few more smaller ones.
Definitely.
That's amazing.
And how long have you been an ER doctor for?
Oh, man, I've been a doctor in
practice for about seven or eight years now.
So you've been a doctor
the last, let's say, eight years.
During that time, what's the most
fascinating thing that you've learned about people?
Oh, man, that's a great question.
Actually, I don't know why this popped in
my mind, but now I think about it.
This is a good one.
People don't care about anything when their health
is on the line other than their health.
And that's actually really important because we
can really get caught up in our pursuit
for business and money, right?
And that's great because we talked
about doing good things with it, right?
But don't get so caught up that
you forget the fact that you've got
health and your family's got health.
And that's something to be appreciated
now because I've seen patients who have
millions of dollars and they just struck
it big and millions are coming in.
And they're telling me, you know,
Doc, that means nothing to me.
I wish I could just have my belly back.
This guy had stomach cancer because I'd trade it
all if I could have my belly back, right?
So I've learned that when it comes
to humans, when it comes to people,
we all want what we want and that's great.
But let's not forget what we have.
And what we have is health.
So I think that is important to create
a balance in our life as we pursue,
as we take our health and
make big things out of ourselves.
Let's not forget our health too.
So you had gone to school originally to become
a medical professional and you are an ER doctor,
but you also became an entrepreneur.
So what was the turning point
like in your life that told you,
I kind of want to go out on
my own, invest in myself and start creating companies?
Well, I guess the first time I felt like,
I needed to go from
being a doctor to a businessman
was actually when I was doing
a medical trip in East Africa.
I got invited with a small church
to go and see people in the villages.
And long story short is while I was out there,
I realized it was just one person
as one doctor with a medical bag.
I could really scratch the surface of any real problem.
Now, I'd like to think it's
meaningful for the people we saw.
We saw about 250 people a day.
But I realized if I could learn how to build
institutions and understand operations,
I can build entities that last
a lot longer than I can last.
So I came back into the country with this
inspiration to learn not just how to be a doctor,
but how do I create the
entire facility and then grow that.
So in the previous answer, you brought up scaling,
and that's something that a lot of
entrepreneurs really struggle with in today's world.
You know, maybe they have a great idea.
They start that business, but they really don't
know how to really scale it and grow it.
So what's the biggest thing that
you implement throughout the companies that
you're a part of to really
scale them in terms of growth?
Maybe it's people, maybe it's capital.
What's the secret to scaling?
How can you really take a business
from six to seven figures in today's world?
If you're doing everything yourself, you only
have so much hours in a day, right?
So if you want to scale, you need
to have somebody to replace some of your tasks.
And even if it's not one
person to do everything you can do,
they need to be some of the parts, right?
Like, for example, I've got a friend with a clothing store
and is doing very well and he's there all the time.
Now, how is he going to open more locations
if he doesn't have somebody to work in that store?
Right now, how are you going to get someone to work
in that store if you don't know how to select people,
if you don't know how to train people?
So this comes into a new skill set,
which is creating a standard operating procedure, right?
If you look at some of the biggest
companies in the world like McDonald's, even around here,
Chick-fil-A, Microsoft, they have it written in a book.
Everything you say, everything you do needs to be written and
standardized so that you can hand this book to someone else
who can then hire and do everything that you say.
Now, that being said, while that's a requirement, no one's going
to run the company the way you're going to run the company.
That's why even with those same standard operating procedures,
the CEO changes and the company goes down, right?
So you still have to be able to provide supervision as the owner,
as a CEO, to make sure the company is heading in the right direction.
Sometimes that's as simple as, I say simple, but as
seemingly simple as making sure you're inspiring all of your managers.
And if you're an absentee leader, or if you're cracking the whip a
little too hard, or you're not cracking it enough, or whatever the dynamic is,
if you're not inspiring your people, providing the right benefits,
or the right information, or the right tools they need,
then your organization is going to
keep suffering because you're not there.
So to answer the question to scale, it's going to be understanding
how to standardize what you do, how to train people what you do,
and how to select the right people
that can be the sum of your parts.
Wow.
What's the greatest lesson that you've ever
learned from a mentor throughout your career?
What's the best piece of advice
that you've ever received from a mentor?
Maybe it's an influential figure, a father, anybody in your life that
gave you some advice, taught you a lesson, what would that be?
I think the biggest thing I
ever heard was from my father.
And it was when I
had got accepted into med school.
I was ready for it, but he
said, son, it's going to be difficult.
And I'm like, eh, I got this, right?
I'm ready.
He goes, no, you don't know.
You don't know yet, but it's going to be difficult.
And he said, if you do it for yourself, when the going gets
tough and you stumble and fall, you may not want to get back up.
You might say to yourself, hey, it's comfortable down here.
I'll just stick around for a while.
He said, but if you do it carrying the flag of the
people around you, your family, your community, your country, your world, then
don't matter what, when you fall down and you look up and
you see the flag you're carrying, then you'll always get back up.
And he was right.
When things got difficult, I thought about that.
And then giving up or staying
down was never an option for me.
It was so much easier when you're doing
it for somebody else or for a greater purpose.
And it wasn't just for med school.
I think in everything in my life, when I
approach it that way, it's not just for myself.
It's for a greater purpose.
I think it's easier to accomplish the task or
have the resolve that you need to never give up.
It's a beautiful answer.
And I wanted to ask.
What is it?
What has been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
Oh, man.
I actually don't like talking about finances, right?
But there's some good years and there's some bad years.
And sometimes people hear a couple million and
they're like, oh, man, he's got all this money.
It's great money and I'm super excited about it.
But you've got to keep account how much goes to
taxes and how much you're going to reinvest for growth.
So it's not like I can necessarily,
I want to spend it right away.
You know, but we'll say a couple million
in a year and we'll leave it at that.
For sure.
Okay.
Over the last few years, what would you say
is the best financial decision that you ever made?
If there's one particular
decision, maybe it's an investment.
Maybe it was opening a particular business.
What would you say was the
best financial decision that you ever made?
The best financial decision was the first one.
The first business, right?
Do you remember who said it?
I know T. Boone Pickens might
have repeated it in his book.
Or maybe he has credit for saying it.
But the saying goes, the first million is the hardest.
Right?
And it's so true because once
you have money, then you've got comfort.
You can start investing in other projects.
You don't have to work like a dog for a couple years to
get that initial money again to get that match to light the fire.
So the best financial decision I made was
to save a lot and take the risk.
But, of course, you've got to calculate your risk
and you've got to be prepared to lose it.
You've got to have your backup plan.
And you have to say.
If you lose the ego, you say, I'm going to do whatever
it takes to make sure this works and this ship does not sink.
So you can't fear.
Don't fear loss.
Don't fear poverty is what
my father used to tell me.
That way you can work hard, take the money, and not
be too afraid to take the money and invest in a business.
Sometimes you're going to lose.
Sometimes you're going to win.
But if you don't try, you're never going to
learn the skill set you need to keep growing.
Wow.
And what's been your secret
to self-improvement throughout your career?
Regardless of the industry you've been in, but just in general, how have you constantly been able
to get better in terms of knowledge, in terms of perspective, in terms of the people around you?
What is your secret to self-improvement?
I think one thing my father
taught me was to never point fingers.
There's always blame to go around.
But he always made me focus
on what I could do differently.
I mean, oh, that person did
this or this person did that.
Or who are they?
That doesn't matter.
Right?
Because if now you're the one in charge.
It's your project or it's your future.
It doesn't really matter who's to blame.
All that matters is, in a way, just blame yourself.
Say, how could I have
known that that wouldn't have worked?
How could I have seen this disaster
coming or this miscalculation or this failure?
Instead of just blaming everybody else, say, okay, next
time I'm going to make sure this doesn't happen.
Either I'm going to train somebody better.
I'm going to select them better.
I need to do more background information.
I should have worked harder.
So I think always.
Holding yourself accountable is the key to growth.
Because if you always think that you didn't do anything wrong and
everybody else did everything wrong, you're never going to get any better.
Obviously, you've created a bunch of
companies over a bunch of different industries.
And entrepreneurship is hard.
What would you say is the biggest
challenge that you faced as an entrepreneur?
How have you been able to overcome that ultimately?
The biggest challenge as an
entrepreneur is, I guess, different things.
Different phases have different challenges.
The first challenge is, how do I get started?
How do I get the knowledge?
How do I get the money?
And then how do I become the person that's not
going to squander it all if it was handed to me?
How do I become an honest, good person?
That's the hard step.
Because I promise you, I can give somebody
who's like, I want to be an entrepreneur.
Here's $1 million.
And then here's all the books you need.
Or I'll teach you as you go.
And they'll still screw it up.
Because they'll get greedy.
They'll get emotional.
They won't do what they say.
Or they'll sit on their butts
instead of doing the next step.
And they won't meet the deadlines.
I promise you, I can do that.
So you've got to have those things.
But you've got to be the right person that's ready to accept
those things, to build those things, and utilize them as a good leader.
But then later, the hard thing about
entrepreneur is, do I diversify now or later?
Because now you're taking bigger bets.
I might have needed a
couple hundred thousand dollars to start.
Or tens of thousands to start.
Now I'm betting on a million dollar.
And I could lose everything I started with.
And I could financially ruin myself.
Now the stakes are higher.
So the challenge is now,
how do I calculate these risks?
And then I think the bigger challenge is, once you start making so
much money, and you can retire, but you don't because you're built this way.
OK, I've got $10 million in the bank.
Do I retire now?
Could.
But I just spent my whole life
trying to learn how to shake and move.
I'm not built that way now.
So now you've got to ask yourself, well,
how do you find the balance in your life?
That's the challenge.
Are you spending so much time that you
fail to get a relationship and have kids?
Or you had kids and you
didn't spend enough time with them?
Or your parents are now getting older, and you could
have called, you could have wrote, you could have visited.
So then you have to ask yourself,
OK, life is more to it than this.
How do I put it all together?
So I think the challenges for the entrepreneur are
very, very different depending on what stage you're in.
And if you could spend the day with one
influential figure, dead or alive, who would that person be?
Benjamin Franklin.
Man, I would love to meet that guy.
Because not only was he an
intelligent dude that made all these inventions.
We know him from like, oh,
he discovered electricity and all these inventions.
But he was also a
very big statesman and a diplomat.
He single-handedly stopped wars between the
Americans, the French, and the British.
Why?
Because of the money.
Because all three of them respected him.
So if he said, guys, let's talk.
They say, sure, Ben.
For you, let's talk.
So how do you get to that point?
One, you've got to make something of yourself.
One, you've got to be honest.
And then second, you've got to be honest.
You've got to treat everybody fairly.
And people have got to know that,
hey, if he talks, we should listen.
And I think that kind of diplomacy and that type of understanding
of people and that type of ambition to be able to sit,
to bring three of the biggest superpowers back to
the table when they're fighting, I think is very admirable.
So I'd love to meet a guy like
that and hear what he has to say.
And how can I become more like him?
I've never asked this to anyone before, but I'm curious because it
seems like you're very renowned and versatile kind of on your world history.
But what would you say is the best
lesson that you've learned from studying world history?
If there's one particular lesson that you focused on or
that you've studied a lot, what would you say that is?
We just keep getting duped.
We just keep getting fooled
as humans over and over again.
It's the same old story in a new timeline.
People want to rise to power.
People want to take advantage of others.
They want to take advantage
of the poor and the weak.
They want to pit people against each other.
They're constantly making us fight
so they can rise to power.
And we keep falling for the same tricks.
If you keep looking in history, the same tricks
that they've done before we had TV and social media,
whether they walked the streets and walked the streets,
and sold a narrative,
and then they gave yellow journalism
and newspapers to sell a narrative,
or they pushed things on
social media to sell a narrative,
we keep falling for these emotional decisions.
And we keep fighting each other, and
we keep drawing hard lines in the sand.
And we argue over things all
the time that don't really matter.
Instead of doing that, we
should actually find real solutions.
But we can't because we've already determined that
you are on the other side of this,
this ideological argument.
So whatever you say, I'm going to argue with you.
And I wish that as humans we
can look back in history and say,
this is our nature to be tribal.
How do we become more constructive and actually
find it in our nature to work together
and to understand each other and
understand why you're coming from that position,
why I'm coming from this position, and what do we
do about it now to make it better for everybody?
Beautiful answer. Wow.
What's the greatest lesson that your father taught you?
The greatest lesson?
The greatest lesson I learned from my
father is the one I keep saying,
which is don't get caught up with the money.
And you can't say it enough because I've
seen so many people change because they got money.
It's not about the money.
It's about the personal growth.
Who are you as a person?
Because say I had $100 million right
now, and you took it away from me.
Who am I?
How did I get that money?
What's left?
And I'm not saying that you're a man or a
woman if you take away the money tomorrow that you've earned.
Do people still say, man, I love that guy.
He's a great person.
He helped me with this.
He helped me with that.
He looks out for people around him.
He's a good friend.
He's a good family member.
So the number one thing I learned from my father
is, yes, you want to do good in everything you do,
and then money will hopefully become
a byproduct if it's written for you.
But who are you as a person?
That's way more important.
So that way you don't
get caught up in the money.
You don't get caught up in the pursuit of things.
You remember that as you acquire your
businesses and financial strength and political strength,
you're always protecting the most important thing,
which is who you are as a person,
so that when you get
the money, it doesn't change you.
Guys, that wraps up today's episode.
Thank you so much for tuning in.
Be sure to like and subscribe
for tons of amazing content coming soon.
AK, thank you so much for joining us today.
My pleasure.
Thank you.
I guess I'm fairly active on Instagram.
It's just my first initial A
and then my last name, Kudrath, K-U-D-R-A-T-H.
And I actually want to start doing some more
video series on medical-related stuff for the general population
and also car stuff because
everyone's a fan of the cars.
And then we can maybe get you guys
back on to do more business-related things as well.
There we go.
Perfect.